<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: learning | Team Neko]]></title>
  <link href="http://teamneko.github.io/blog/categories/learning/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://teamneko.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-17T09:46:05+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://teamneko.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Shelly Coen and Pilar Huidobro]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[summeroftessie@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[(octo)Pressing Problems]]></title>
    <link href="http://teamneko.github.io/blog/2015/03/20/octo-pressing-problems/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://teamneko.github.io/blog/2015/03/20/octo-pressing-problems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the most fun learning experiences I’ve had while working on our Summer of Code application is getting to work with <a href="http://octopress.org/">octopress</a>. I had previously used it a little bit for my <a href="http://althaire.github.io/">personal blog</a>, but I’d mostly just made a couple of posts and with some help, I was able to set up a new layout.</p>

<p>Working on our team was a whole new challenge. We agreed that it would be a better learning experience for us as a team that if we ran into any trouble, we’d help each other out.</p>

<p>As fun as it has been to learn octopress, I have run into loads of problems! It&rsquo;s not just octopress either, it&rsquo;s git! Practice makes perfect though, right?</p>

<p>The first silly problem I ran into was that I forgot my SSH key password. It shouldn&rsquo;t be that big a deal, right? Just make a new one? <em>It wasn&rsquo;t working though&hellip;</em> I tried a couple of times to get it to work but it just wouldn&rsquo;t. Finally I had to give in and just watch despairingly as my awesome Github streak reset (keeping it up for 6 days was a huge personal achievement), this wasn&rsquo;t going to be a problem that I would solve in one day.</p>

<p>Naturally, the next morning I just tried the <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/generating-ssh-keys/">basic steps</a> I&rsquo;d been following the day before and&hellip; <em>it worked.</em> Why? We shall never know, it&rsquo;s just one of those things.</p>

<center>
<img src="http://teamneko.github.io/images/ProblemsPost/codeworksmeme.jpg"> </center>


<p>The great news was that it worked and I could continue working, right? <strong>Wrong.</strong> I had naïvely thought that I could keep working on the posts I had to do, even without git, because sitting around and waiting for it to fix itself was a huge waste of time.</p>

<blockquote><p>That was a huge mistake and it is one I won&rsquo;t be making <em>ever</em> again.</p></blockquote>

<p>The reason was that was such a terrible mistake was that, of course, in the mean time, Shelly had contributed posts of her own. This meant that I had unwittingly caused a monstrous merge problem, which, to make matters worse, I had no idea how to deal with.</p>

<p>After many struggles, the solution we applied was to make a new folder, clone the repository onto there, move all the edited markdown folders somewhere else (thank goodness I had only edited markdown files!), move all the edited folders into the newly cloned repository folder, add, commit and finally push. It was a pretty crazy solution, and there&rsquo;s probably a better way to do it, but it did the job!</p>

<p>Shelly and I kept running into obstacles on our git journey, and I feel like it&rsquo;s never been more applicable but practice does make perfect. I feel like the more we use it, the less both of us have been breaking things.</p>

<p>Just to make sure we don&rsquo;t run into any snags, I made us a little cheat sheet:</p>

<center>
<img src="http://teamneko.github.io/images/graphics/octopresscheatsheet.png"> </center>


<p>This whole experience brought back memories of solving puzzles as a kid, or getting through a tough dungeon in a Zelda game. I think we just need to keep practising, but it&rsquo;s been a fun experience running into these troubles and having to find solutions.</p>

<p>~Pilar</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
