<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Team Neko]]></title>
  <link href="http://teamneko.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://teamneko.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-24T09:45:25+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://teamneko.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Flood of Good News]]></title>
    <link href="http://teamneko.github.io/blog/2015/03/20/a-flood-of-good-news/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-20T12:09:16+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://teamneko.github.io/blog/2015/03/20/a-flood-of-good-news</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are getting quite a lot of encouraging news already, even though we are only
in the first stages of things.</p>

<p>First off was our experience with Wirsing. I&rsquo;ve mentioned it before, but at the
last Vienna.rb myself and Pilar got up to ask the other rubyists present if
anyone would be interested in coaching us. Clemens from Wirsing was kind enough
to offer, so we emailed with him the following day. Not only was he enthusiastic
to coach us, but so were the other members of Wirsing! They have offered to be a
coaching company for us in every aspect other than providing desks - this being that
they work out of a co-working space here in Vienna.
Fortunately for us, we have been offered desks in a different co-working space,
so this works out quite well! Wirsing only work on projects that they love, and
this is often with a focus on environmental or sociological issues. Their company
tagline is &ldquo;Software for a better future&rdquo; which really is a great starting point
to have.</p>

<p>We have been in contact with Jan Lehnardt, the mentor for the Hoodie project in
rgsoc. A lot of things in my life happen due to fortuitous timing. At concat, I
sat beside a fellow with a rather impressive beard. I was introduced to him and
we briefly spoke, and then a few minutes later he got an email confirming Hoodie
for RGSoC. I told him about myself and Pilar&rsquo;s upcoming application and asked him
all about the project, what it entails, and whether it is suitable for beginners.
If I hadn&rsquo;t been siting next to him at that moment I might not have ended up
speaking to him about RGSoC at all.
I was lucky enough to meet several other people from Hoodie that day too, they&rsquo;re all
really great people and I love the ethos of the company. They give a detailed
explanation on their <a href="http://hood.ie/about/">about page</a> but the basic gist could
be summarised in this particular paragraph;</p>

<blockquote><p>The reason why Hoodie exists is that everyone involved in this project wants to
help make the web a better place for everyone, and everyone of us is convinced
that web development should be accessible to as many people as possible.</p></blockquote>

<p>They have a big focus on diversity and inclusiveness, something that is so
important, but not always a given.</p>

<p>All in all, we have quite a lot of great things going our way already. I really
hope this streak continues and that we get accepted for RGSoC. It really would be
wonderful to work with so many enthusiastic, intelligent, and lovely people!</p>

<p>Shelly</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vienna.rb #22]]></title>
    <link href="http://teamneko.github.io/blog/2015/03/05/vienna-dot-rb-number-22/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-05T19:42:20+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://teamneko.github.io/blog/2015/03/05/vienna-dot-rb-number-22</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Vienna.rb is always quite a fun evening. The first time I (Shelly) went, I went
alone and promptly squirrelled myself away in a corner to listen to the talks.<br/>
I needn&rsquo;t have been so nervous! Everyone at vienna.rb is super friendly and welcoming.
On this particular first night, Floor Drees (who has so very kindly offered to be
our supervisor for RGSoC) came over and introduced me to Pilar. We started talking
about how we both want to apply for summer of code, our goals, and I think the
conversation also wandered towards favourite video games.</p>

<p>But, I digress. Flash forward to Vienna.rb #22. This came the day after Team Neko&rsquo;s
first meeting in Cafe Neko. As Pilar mentioned in the previous post, we were both
excited to meet Luca Guidi to ask some questions about the Lotus project and to
find out what is expected. Luca was very open to chat to us and we spoke over pizza
in between some talks. It was a pleasure to meet Luca, and the chat with him only
served to add to our motivation and excitement about what is (possibly) to come!</p>

<p>The talks that evening were, as always, quite interesting.</p>

<p>The first talk was by Stefan Haslinger. <em>Mr. 100 000 Volts gift-wraps Rubies and Opals</em>
This talk was quite informative but I have to admit that it went a teeny bit over
my head this time. Sometimes the level of information is just that teeny bit out
of my grasp so I don&rsquo;t fully follow things&hellip;YET. What I did follow was very
interesting!</p>

<p>Next up was Pilar&rsquo;s brother, Ramon. He presented his talk *How Teaching Kids Made
Me a Better Developer&#8221; which he was due to present at concat() in Salzburg the
following Saturday. I have written about this talk in my post about concat, which
I have not yet posted.<br/>
Ramon&rsquo;s talk was great. The subject matter is something that I identify quite a lot
with, given my background of teaching kids, albeit teaching English rather than
anything technical. It was wonderful to get some tips on how I can use one area
to help the other.</p>

<p>Then, two wonderful ladies who are applying for summer of code got up to ask if
anyone present would like to join our list of coaches for the duration of the
programme. I mean their. Dangit, I&rsquo;ve never been good at writing in the third
person.<br/>
As a result of this, we have gotten the support of not just one more
person, but a whole company! The folk of wirsing.io are really enthusiastic about
helping us out over the summer. Added to our original list which already had a
few people, we have a fantastically strong support network behind us if we are
lucky enough to be accepted onto summer of code.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s quite humbling that so many people are not just willing, but eager to
help and support us in this endeavor. It&rsquo;s wonderful inspiration to pay it forward
and again, more proof that I really should not have been at all nervous the first
night I ventured to a vienna.rb!</p>

<p>Laura Gaetano was the last speaker of the evening, with a talk that opened the
evening&rsquo;s discussions. The topic was <em>Github as a Project Management Tool</em>. The
talk explained the way in which Laura and her team use Github to track things, and
the discussion broadened to include experience people have with Trello and
Blossom. As a beginner in this industry, I found it really helpful to get an overview
of how to effectively manage projects with some personal feedback thrown in.</p>

<p>This was a particularly encouraging edition of Vienna.rb. Excitement is building
for our upcoming application!</p>

<p>Shelly</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our First RGSoC Meeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://teamneko.github.io/blog/2015/03/05/first-meeting/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-05T19:31:40+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://teamneko.github.io/blog/2015/03/05/first-meeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After the hustle and bustle of February (more like getting <a href="http://rubyhabits.github.io">Ruby Habits</a> off the ground) was slowly dying down, we finally took our first step and set up a date for us to sit down and talk about our plans for this year&rsquo;s <a href="http://railsgirlssummerofcode.org">Rails Girls Summer of Code</a>.</p>

<p>I came to the meeting very excited to tell Shelly that I had just seen that <em>Lotus</em> had gotten accepted as a project for RGSoC. I had seen <em>Luca Guidi</em> give a talk on Lotus at a previous Vienna.rb meeting, and I remember thinking at the time,</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Wow! That&rsquo;s really cool! I really want to be good enough some day to be able to do something like that, build my own framework.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Of course, at the time, I dismissed the thought and left Lotus as a mere note in my book, but now with Rails Girls Summer of Code, that actually had a chance of happening! To make things even better, Luca was attending the next Vienna.rb meeting, giving us the perfect opportunity to meet him personally and ask him what exactly he would expect us to work on if we were to take on the Lotus project.</p>

<p>Our first decision as a team was that it would be a really good idea to start a blog, even before applying, so we could record decisions we had made together, things we had learned and already start chronicling our journey into the world of tech. We kind of panicked on the name picking, and figured that we should pick something quick, because we&rsquo;d be changing our name later and if we didn&rsquo;t, we&rsquo;d both go home, obsess about it and never start the blog.</p>

<p>We went with Team Neko as our meting was taking place at Café Neko, the local cat coffeehouse.</p>

<center>
<img src="http://teamneko.github.io/images/Post1/Luca3.jpg"> 
</center>


<p><code>After hours of stealing glances at the adorable inhabitants of the cat café, we were finally able to tame Luca, a majestic maine coon who secretly loves chin scratches.</code></p>

<p>All in all, we had a very successful evening. Together we looked at the projects, talked about which ones we liked and which ones we felt capable of doing. We also had a look at last year&rsquo;s team&rsquo;s blogs to get some inspiration (<em>and it worked! We started this blog, didn&rsquo;t we?</em>) Best of all, we got to know a lot about each other. In a lot of aspects we compliment each other and in others we&rsquo;re so similar that it&rsquo;s uncanny. I have a feeling we&rsquo;re gonna make a great team!</p>

<p>~Pilar</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
